

### zensar

# Narendra Chaudhary

Email Id –
narendra.chaudhary1@zensar.co
m
Ph:9705343670
Location:Hyderabad



#### **Summary**

Narendra has 7.04 yrs of industry experience, served 6+ clients across 3 geographies in key areas like development, maintenance, etc.

He is well versed with major development technologies & process like – Software development and maintaining Web Applications. Using JAVA-J2EE, technologies that include JDBC, Servlets, JSP, Spring, Spring-boot, MyBatis, Hibernate, Amazon Web Services.

LinkedIn:

#### Role History

- Sr, Software engineer Currently Working for Zensar **Broadridge(UBS)** [Nov 2021- July 2023]
- Sr. Software engineer, **Keste Software Private Limited (Western Union-VMS)** [January 2020-February 2021]
- Sr. Software engineer, **Ibaseit Software Solutions Pvt. Ltd.**(Cloudflux) [April 2019- January 2020]
- Sr. Software engineer, **Prime Ki Software Solutions Pvt. Limited(PRISE/PRIMEPAS)** [November 2016- March 2019]
- Software engineer, NeoApp Technologies Pvt. Limited(NeoStock) [June 2015-October 2016]

#### **Education**

• BTech in computer science [2011-2015]

Core		Category	Primary skills	Secondary skills
		Verticals	INSURANCE & STOCK	Analysis
			Market	
		Domains	Development using <b>J2EE</b> ,	Maintenance
			Spring 3.2.8, Spring-	
			Boot,MyBatis,	
	comp etenci es/ski lls		Collection, Amazon Web	
			Services etc.	
		Tools & Techniques	SOAP, Web Services	SoapUi and Postman
		Databases	MSSQL, MYSQL	Queries
		Programming skills	Core Java, MVC	Design Patterns
			Architecture	

#### **Expertise**

- Developing of new software
- Enhancement and Maintenance of existing software

#### **Awards**

• Movers and Shakers award from Executive VP. Insurance Solutions

#### Experience Sum mary

- **Functionality Development** of new product insurance application, *Sr. Software engineer* [Nov 2016 to April 2019]
  - o Worked as Developer, Team Lead, Solution Provider, Domain Expertise.
  - Used Spring IOC, Mybatis, Angular1.x, REST Web service, JBoss Drools, Jackrabbit (CMS),
     Docmosis (Document Merging Tool), Spring OXM, XSLT, XSD, MySql, Wildfly server, Eclipse,
     Tortoise SVN.
- Functionality Enhancement and Maintenance for VMS(Verification and Modification System) of Western Union company, *Sr. Software engineer* [Jan 2020 to Jan 2021]
  - Worked as analyst and Developer.
  - Used Java 8, Spring Boot, Hibernate, MySql, Maven, atlassian-JIRA, Git, Tomcat, Drools, Jenkins etc.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Project – Development of product PRISE/PRIMEPAS [Nov 2016 to April 2019]

Role: Sr. Software engineer

**Project Description:** PRIME's Policy Administration System is a SaaS based insurance application built on modern technology that supports multiple lines of business (both Personal and Commercial Lines) across a new business and policy processing. It provides users with a flexible and configurable environment to create their own products to meet the rapidly changing product requirements in the market by automating the entire life insurance policy, including integration with third party applications. PRIME's Policy Administration System meets the requirements for all types and sizes of insurance companies in the Property and Casualty Industry.

Key activities performed: performed development using Spring IOC, Mybatis, Angular1.x, REST Web service, JBoss Drools, Jackrabbit (CMS), Docmosis (Document Merging Tool), Spring OXM, XSLT, XSD, MySql, Wildfly server, Eclipse, Tortoise SVN.

- ❖ Involved in analyzing and development of the application.
- Worked as Developer, Team Lead, Solution Provider, Domain Expertise.

#### Technology/Skills/Tools used

- <u>Tools:</u> Eclipse, SVN, Postman, JIRA, Wildfly server, Docmosis
- Technologies: Java, Spring, MyBatis, MySql, Maven, AngularJs etc.
- <u>Skills:</u> Analysis and Development

#### Project – Functionality Development of VMS(Verification and Modification) for Western Union [Jan 2020 to Jan 2021]

Role: Sr. Software engineer

**Project Description:** Verification and Modification System(VMS) is the last step in the CCT workflow where an order can be modified before it goes for further processing. All the payment orders that originates across the WUBS network and passing through CCT will be redirected through VMS.

Key activities performed: performed development and maintenance activities using Java 8, Spring Boot, Hibernate, MySql, Maven, atlassian-JIRA, Git, Tomcat, Drools, Jenkins etc.

- ❖ Involved in analyzing and adding rules in the application.
- Performed research work on solving complex technical issue faced in the system.
- ❖ Helped in migrating codes to from lower to upper Java version.

#### Technology/Skills/Tools used

- <u>Tools:</u> Eclipse, GIT, Postman, JIRA, Tomcat, Drools
- <u>Technologies:</u> Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, MySql, Maven
- Skills: Analysis and Development
- AWS: Amazon web services like Lambda, DynamoDB, S3, CloudWatch etc.

## Project – Zensar Technologies -functionality Development of UBS(carma-integration team) for Broadridge [November 2021 to till date]

Role: Sr. Software engineer

Project Description: carma-integrator is system which was used to capture different events based on data changes, and filter

the required data and forward to downstream systems. Used AWS SQS service to send and receive commands, DynamoDB for storing records, AWS Lambda for processing data, S3 for maintaining files and AWS CloudWatch for monitoring logs.

Key activities performed: performed development and maintenance activities using Java 8, Lambda, DynamoDB SQS, S3, CloudWatch etc.

- ❖ Involved in writing filter logic in the application.
- Worked on adding Test cases for the application.

#### Technology/Skills/Tools used

- <u>Tools:</u> Eclipse, GIT, Postman, JIRA
- <u>Technologies:</u> Java, Spring Boot, Maven
- <u>Skills:</u> Analysis and Development
- AWS: Amazon web services like Lambda, DynamoDB, S3, CloudWatch etc.

#### Major achievements

• Awarded "Movers and Shakers" award from Executive VP, Insurance Solutions in 2016-2019 by Prime KI Software Solutions Private Limited

#### Any client appreciation

• Recognized by client for meeting timeline and providing outstanding alternate solutions required for the improvement of the application.